<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>more or less insightful</title>
    <link>https://www.ooseel.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on more or less insightful</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 13:20:35 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ooseel.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>esBPF: Stress-Testing compares Software-Offload with iptables</title>
      <link>https://www.ooseel.net/2022/11/esbpf-stress-testing-compares-software-offload-with-iptables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 13:20:35 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ooseel.net/2022/11/esbpf-stress-testing-compares-software-offload-with-iptables/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            esBPF project has been over one year and it began with the idea that Is it worth filtering ingress packets on Software-Offload layer instead of Network Stack? Software-Offload is similar to Hardware-Offload, but it works in ethernet driver. Now time to do Stress-testing since its prototype was released and the comparison object will be iptables.
Before walking through the article, let me define a few short terms against typing exhausting long terms,
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build upstream Ubuntu Kernel for Arm64 Raspberry-Pi</title>
      <link>https://www.ooseel.net/2022/11/build-upstream-ubuntu-kernel-for-arm64-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:41:09 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ooseel.net/2022/11/build-upstream-ubuntu-kernel-for-arm64-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Whole processes, git cloning the right codebase from a repository, installing all the packages, kernel configuration, and finally go building are such a challenge for beginners like me. Fortunately, Ubuntu Kernel Team provides an easy system for building kernel though.
In this article, we are going to look at some requirements. In more detail, try installing build tools, get ready, and building :-)
Get ready for upstream kernel and environment Canonical, a company mainly supports Ubuntu distro maintains its Kernel sources at Launchpad, but for Raspberry Pi, it&#39;s maintained at this repository.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>집에서 English Speaking 연습하기</title>
      <link>https://www.ooseel.net/2022/03/training-english-speaking-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 23:44:05 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ooseel.net/2022/03/training-english-speaking-at-home/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            해외 여행 준비로 English Speaking과 관련된 여러가지 방법을 찾아보고 있다. 한달 뒤에 출국 예정이므로 기본 대화가 가능하고 틀려도 자신감있게 말하기 위해 다음과 같은 방법을 생각해봤는데...
 오프라인 언어 교환에 나간다. 전화 영어를 해본다. 미드 쉐도잉 온라인 언어 교환 앱 사용하기.  1. 오프라인 언어 교환 참석 나와 맞지 않는다. 예전에 자신감없고 speaking이 익숙하지 않은 상태에서 나가니까 2시간 내내 아무말도 안하고 free talking인데 할 얘기가 없어서 Ok, Yes, No 만 하다가 왔다.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>월간 인사이트 - 2021년 7월호</title>
      <link>https://www.ooseel.net/2021/07/hashtag-monthly-insight-2021-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 15:39:12 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ooseel.net/2021/07/hashtag-monthly-insight-2021-07/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            General  삶에 대한 질문? 그 답을 찾다: 광고기획자 박웅현  Youtube에 올라온 EBS 영상 클립이고 총 #1, #2로 구성되어 있다. 청중들로부터 여러가지 질문을 받아 QNA 하는 형식으로 되어 있는데 깊은 생각을 하게끔 만드는 답변을 많이 주신다. 내가 존경하는 분이며 삶에 대해 자신&#39;만&#39;의 답을 찾길 원하신다면 추천한다.    
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cache Memory QnA</title>
      <link>https://www.ooseel.net/2021/07/hashtag-cache-memory-qna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 13:07:43 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ooseel.net/2021/07/hashtag-cache-memory-qna/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            잘못된 정보는 https://github.com/memnoth/me/issues/1에 남겨주시기 바랍니다.
List  Startup에서 D-cache=off 임에도 불구하고 cache line invalidation 하는 목적이 뭔가요?  QnA Q. 아래 코드에서 D-cache = off 임에도 불구하고 cache line invalidation 하는 목적이 뭔가요? 1// &amp;#39;head.S&amp;#39; of linux kernel 5.10 2/* 3* Kernel startup entry point. 4* --------------------------- 5* 6* The requirements are: 7* MMU = off, D-cache = off, I-cache = on or off, 8* x0 = physical address to the FDT blob.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why MMU and D-Cache must be off at Startup point</title>
      <link>https://www.ooseel.net/2021/07/why-mmu-and-d-cache-must-be-off-at-startup-point-in-arm64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 22:31:36 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ooseel.net/2021/07/why-mmu-and-d-cache-must-be-off-at-startup-point-in-arm64/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Q. 아래와 같이 startup point에서 MMU 와 D-Cache의 상태가 off 여야 하는데 이유가 뭔가요? 1 // &amp;#39;head.S&amp;#39; of linux kernel 5.10 2 /* 3* Kernel startup entry point. 4* --------------------------- 5* 6* The requirements are: 7* MMU = off, D-cache = off, I-cache = on or off, 8* x0 = physical address to the FDT blob. 9* 10* This code is mostly position independent so you call this at 11* __pa(PAGE_OFFSET).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>월간 인사이트 - 2021년 6월호</title>
      <link>https://www.ooseel.net/2021/06/hashtag-montly-insight-2021-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ooseel.net/2021/06/hashtag-montly-insight-2021-06/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            General  &#39;월간 인사이트&#39; 시작  안도형님이 작성하신 This month I Learnd을 보고 시작했다. 포스트하는건 귀찮지만 인사이트를 얻은 글에 대해 월 단위로 정리하여 공유하기에 좋은 방법이라 생각한다. 기억속에 고이 잠든 인사이트 넘치는 글들이 너무나 많다!   평범한 일상이 소중한 이유  퇴근 후 맥주 한 잔, 저녁 노을을 보며 뛸 수 있는 여유. 30대에 들어서며 20대에 가졌던 생각이 많이 바뀌었다. 20대에는 지금의 나는 내 인생에서 두번 다시 오지 않아!라며 악착같이 열심히 경험쌓으며 살았다.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design SIOCGIFADDR on IPv6 socket</title>
      <link>https://www.ooseel.net/2021/02/design-siocgifaddr-on-ipv6-socket/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 21:26:31 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ooseel.net/2021/02/design-siocgifaddr-on-ipv6-socket/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As some of you already know SIOCGIFADDR isn&#39;t supported on IPv6 socket although SIOCSIFADDR is. For sure there is a reason linux kernel doesn&#39;t do so but it&#39;s worth to build up by our hands, then we get to know much more in detail. This is good for us as a studying purpose rather than use in product.
We define simple ideas with some requirements, then look at kernel patch and a demo.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020년을 되돌아 보는 글</title>
      <link>https://www.ooseel.net/2020/12/look-back-to-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 07:07:07 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ooseel.net/2020/12/look-back-to-2020/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            1년을 되돌아 보는 행동은 언제나 낯설고 긴장된다. 자기 반성을 위해 지난 1년간의 활동을 객관적으로 바라봐야 하는데 이 곳에 말은 못해도 가슴 쓰린 기억들을 끄집어 내야하니 말이다. 이 글은 **나**를 되돌아 보는 글이다.
9월부터 실내암벽 등반을 다시 시작했다. 지금은 2.5단계로 인해 쉬고 있지만 1월에 그만둔 뒤로 8개월만이었다. 회사-집-공부 패턴으로 몇 달을 지내니 스트레스가 풀리지 않아 불면증에 슬럼프까지 겹쳤는데 자존감 측면에서 확실히 운동하고 안 하고의 차이가 존재한다. 땀을 확 빼고 집에 갈 때 느끼는 밤 공기의 상쾌함, 이 느낌은 여전히 내가 살아 존재하는 느낌을 준다.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tricky Signal Tracing in Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.ooseel.net/2020/12/tricky-signal-tracing-in-kernel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 21:35:10 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ooseel.net/2020/12/tricky-signal-tracing-in-kernel/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have you ever experienced such horrible signals between core processes which might crash a whole system? I had done. Unknown signals are a kind of critical issue in product.
Someone says &amp;quot;Better safe than sorry&amp;quot;. I like that quote. Even though software world is totally chaotic on bugs, we should at least try some approaches being safe. Especially signals. They never log while on their way unless we trigger so that could quietly stab your back one day if you are off the guard.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim Pinky and Programmable Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://www.ooseel.net/2020/08/vim-pinky-and-programmable-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:01:30 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ooseel.net/2020/08/vim-pinky-and-programmable-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I use my left pinky to jump back and forth in vim with cscope, ctags + vim comb a lot everyday. Especially ctrl + t, o, ] and so on. However, it has been hurt slightly. I thought that it might be by the use of the pinky a lot, so that looked for a solution in Google. Firstly, I could have modified my input method program a bit such that swap between Ctrl and Caps Lock, but felt frustrated all the steps code level to testing.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GTK&#43; Workshop in Daejeon</title>
      <link>https://www.ooseel.net/2019/01/gtk-workshop-in-daejeon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 13:20:35 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ooseel.net/2019/01/gtk-workshop-in-daejeon/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, everyone!
There is a meetup named Cron-a-thon held by Ubuntu-KR Daejeon team every 2 weeks. However, I put the workshop on the table at the meetup 3 months ago. The administrators and I talked about the organization of an event for the beginners who were into how to build a GTK+ application in Python. That was the beginning of the workshop.
Before we talk about the workshop, let&#39;s look at goods a bit.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
